## Marshall Asch

marshallasch.ca

hello@marshallasch.ca

**Ƴ** @MarshallAsch

in/MarshallAsch

@MarshallAsch



I am a Master of Computer Science with a love for wireless mesh networks and Infrastructure as Code. Over the past several years I have been working on a project to help close the digital divide in Northern Canada with Dr. Dan Gillis.

The other academic area of interest to me is bringing over the knowledge, skills, and experiences that have been developed in industry and applying them in an Academic setting. Whether that be to improve repeatability and maintainability, or to provide teaching resources that do not require access to the internet. I have a passion for command-line tools, networking, servers, and open source projects. Most of my work has been on cli tools, DevOps tasks, and backend systems.

### **Education**

2019 – 2022 M.Sc. Computer Science, University of Guelph, Canada in Mesh Networking.

B.Comp. (Hons) Computer Science, University of Guelph, Canada.

Degree with Distinction Recognition for Outstanding Academic Performance.

## **Open Source Projects**

10/2021 - Present OO Resources Offline Open source teaching resource to provide interactive course content and development dependencies in one place that does not require

internet access.

05/2021 - Present **ns-3 Github CI pipeline**  Continuous development tool to verify that modules

built of the ns-3 network simulator compile and run as intended.

ns-3 Static Access Frequency Module Implemented and maintaining a module for the ns-3 network simulator.

network simulator.

liquidctl maintainer Active Maintainer on the python liquid cooler controller

CLI application

2021 - Present **Botomir maintainer ()** Active Maintainer on the nodeJS Discord Bot application

### **Certification and Training**

2020 - Present

2021 Moo1 - MongoDB Basics Course. MonogoDB University.

M103 - MongoDB Basic Cluster Administration Course. MonogoDB University.

M121 - MongoDB Aggregation Framework Course. MonogoDB University.

## **Employment History**

05/2022 – Present **DevOps Engineer**, Plex.tv.

01/2021 – 06/2021 Graduate Teaching Assistant (Compilers), University of Guelph, ON.

09/2020 – 12/2020 **Graduate Teaching Assistant (Cloud Computing)**, University of Guelph, ON.

09/2019 – 08/2020 Left Mitacs Accelerate Intern, University of Guelph, ON.

## **Employment History (continued)**

09/2019 - 12/2019	■ Graduate Teaching Assistant (Microcomputers), University of Guelph, ON.
05/2019 - 08/2019	■ University of Guelph Mitacs Accelerate Intern, Left, Maple Ridge, BC.
01/2019 - 04/2019	<b>Lead Developer and Undergraduate Research Assistant</b> , Working on the eNuk project, University of Guelph, ON.
	■ Undergraduate Teaching Assistant (Introduction to Computer Applications), University of Guelph, ON.
05/2018 - 08/2018	Mobile App Developer, Left, Maple Ridge, BC.
05/2017 - 08/2017	■ IT Student, Lakeridge Health, Oshawa, ON.
06/2016 - 08/2016	High Ropes Instructor, Camp New Moon, ON
06/2015 - 08/2015	High Ropes Instructor, Camp New Moon, ON
06/2014 - 08/2014	High Ropes Instructor, Camp New Moon, ON

# Volunteer and Extra-Curricular Experience

## Volunteering

J	
01/2021 - Present	<b>Road2IR</b> , Provided technical and networking infrastructure advice.
10/2019	Ontario University Fair, Represented the University of Guelph, Toronto,ON.
09/2019 - 04/2020	<b>Guelph Coding Community</b> , Student club executive, Guelph, ON.
09/2019 - 12/2019	Climbing Gym Monitor, University of Guelph, ON.
12/2019	Major League Hacking, Local Hack Day event Organizer, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.
12/2018	Major League Hacking, Local Hack Day event Organizer, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.
09/2018 - 04/2020	Society of Computing and Information Science, System Administrator, University of Guelph, ON.
04/2017 - 06/2018	Full Stack Developer, ActivNtel, Guelph, ON.
01/2016 - 02/2017	Climbing Gym Monitor, University of Guelph, ON.
09/2016 - 06/2017	Web Developer, NGTronix, Guelph, ON.

### Committees

09/2019 - 03/2022	IT Strategy Advisory Committee. University of Guelph, ON.
01/2018 - 04/2019	<b>Roboticon Planning Committee</b> Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.
09/2017 - 04/2019	Computer Infrastructure Committee School of Computer Science, University of Guelph, ON.
09/2018 - 04/2019	<b>Curriculum Committee</b> School of Computer Science, University of Guelph, ON.

# **Awards and Recognitions**

05/2022	<b>D.F. Forster Magisteriate Medal Nominee</b> , Nominated for the 2022 D.F. Forster Magiste-
	riate Meda, the University of Guelph's highest graduate convocation honour.

09/2020 University of Guelph GSA Conference Runner up, Awarded to the two runner-up presenters for the student run conference.

## Awards and Recognitions (continued)

04/2020

- **Erin Angus Graduate Student Award**. Awarded to a graduate student for making significant contributions to student life by Graduate Student Association.
- **CEPS Dean's Tri-Council Scholarship**, (\$5,000) Deans Scholarship awarded to NSERC award holders, University of Guelph, ON.
- Canada Graduate Scholarships-Master's Program, (\$17,500) Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC) Scholarship, University of Guelph, ON.
- 02/2020
- **Ontario Graduate Scholarship**, (\$5,000) A merit based academic scholarship, University of Guelph, ON.
- 05/2019
- College of Engineering and Physical Sciences Society of Excellence, Demonstrated academic excellence and outstanding contributions to the university community, University of Guelph, ON.
- College of Engineering and Physical Science Deans Honours List, University of Guelph, ON. F15, W16, F16, W17, F17, W18, F18, W19
- 10/2018 **Dr. James Linders Scholarship**. (\$500) Awarded for achieving the highest third year average by the School of Computer Science, University of Guelph, ON.
- 09/2015 University of Guelph Entrance Scholarship. (\$2,000) Awarded for being admitted with an average greater than 85% by the University of Guelph, ON.

#### **Research Grants**

- o3/2022 **eCampus Virtual Learning Strategy Grant**, (\$50,000) Research grant to develop open source, open teaching resources.
- 04/2020 Northern Scientific Training Program. (\$2,150) Awarded to conduct fieldwork in Northern Canada by Polar Knowledge Canada.
- 04/2019 Northern Scientific Training Program. (\$2,307) Awarded to conduct fieldwork in Northern Canada by Polar Knowledge Canada.

### **Non Academic Presentations**

- 09/2020 Introduction to Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- o3/2020 MSc. Seminar Incorporation of Human Mobility in Data Replication Schemes in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- 09/2019 Advanced Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
  - Introduction to BASH and Git, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.
- Major League Hacking Localhost Workshop, Society of Computing and Information Science, Guelph, ON.
- 11/2018 Mesh Networking, Guelph Coding Community, Guelph, ON.

### Research Publications

### **Conference Proceedings**

Asch, M., Versluis, A., Gillis, D., & McCuaig, J. (2022). A self contained, interactive open educational resource for object oriented programming. In *Inted2022 proceedings* (pp. 5781–5788).

Odi:10.21125/inted.2022.1481

- Savić, I., **Asch**, **M.**, Rourke, K., Safari, F., Houlding, P., de Veubeke, J. F., ... Gillis, D. (2022). M-ODD: A standard protocol for reporting MANET related models, simulations, and findings. In W. Bao, X. Yuan, L. Gao, T. H. Luan, & D. B. J. Choi (Eds.), *Ad hoc networks and tools for IT* (Vol. 428, pp. 114–129). Series Title: Lecture Notes of the Institute for Computer Sciences, Social Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering. 6 doi:10.1007/978-3-030-98005-4\_9
- Asch, M., Seymour, P. F., Ernst, J., & Gillis, D. (2019). Incorporation of Node Mobility in Data Replication Schemes in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. In 2019 IEEE 10th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile Communication Conference (IEMCON) (pp. 0230–0236). Oral presentation and Preceding. Odo::10.1109/IEMCON.2019.8936268
- Durish, N., Gillis, D., Seymour, P. F., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Raturi, S., ... Ernst, J. (2019). Bridging the Digital Divide in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Labrador research forum*, Happy Valley-Goose Bay, Labrador, Canada.
- Gillis, D., Durish, N., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Knarr, J., Samuels, J., ... Harper, S. L. (2019). Supporting Community-Based Monitoring with Technology in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Labrador research forum*, Happy Valley-Goose Bay, Labrador, Canada.
- Durish, N., Gillis, D., Seymour, P. F., Rourke, K., **Asch**, **M.**, Raturi, S., ... Ernst, J. (2018). Bridging the Digital Divide to Support Community-Based Monitoring in the Circumpolar North [abstract]. In *Arcticnet*, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.

#### **Conference Presentations**

- **Asch**, M., Lin, X., & Gillis, D. (2020). Impact of Social Interactions on Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. Graduate Students Association Virtual Conference, Guelph, Canada.
- **Asch**, **M.**, Rourke, K., Seymour, P. F., Durish, N., Flowers, C., Wood, M., ... Ernst, J. (2019). Bridging the Digital Divide with Mobile Ad Hoc Networks in the Circumpolar North. Western Student Research Conference, London, Canada.

### Skills

Languages Java, sql, BASH, Languages Java, sql, BASH, Languages

Databases Mysql, MongoDB.

Frameworks Express[S, Discord[S, ns-3, Nginx Web Server, Spring Boot

Tools git, GitHub Actions, Bitbucket Pipelines, aws, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, Docker-Compose.

### References

Available on Request

Last updated: November 12, 2022